

Hector Torres

hitalz@icloud.com +1 (956) 279 3348 https://hitalz.github.io

Profile

As an experienced individual in the technology field, I can contribute towards the growth of organizations with my knowledge in systems administration, troubleshooting, testing, and programming. By being self-started and self-motivated I've been able to evaluate and integrate many systems, and easily adapt to company procedures.

Skills

Systems: G Suite, Office365, Jamf, GoToAssist, osTicket, cPanel, AD, UniFi, WinBox/RouterOS, Joomla, Wordpress, Github, JumpCloud. Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL, Swift, Bash, PowerShell. Databases: MySQL, SQL Server. Libraries: jQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tachyons. Operating/Virtual Systems: macOS, UNIX/Linux, Windows, Windows Server, VirtualBox, Parallels. Cloud services: Amazon Web Services, Microsoft Azure, Google Cloud Platform. Spoken Languages: Bilingual; English & Spanish full proficiency.

Experience

Almanza Villarreal Forwarding, Hidalgo, Texas

Systems Administrator

November 2015 - Present

Perform all levels of hardware and software support to Windows and macOS machines to 130+ users, both locally and remotely. Maintain current assets inventory. Prepare and deploy new computer equipment.

- Provide support on printing issues, internet connectivity, Office 365, G Suite, and many other applications.
- Provide support to remote users via GoToAssist, phone, email and instant messaging.
- Document support inquiries via osTicket Support Ticket System.
- Conduct workshops and training sessions to staff on current applications.
- Elaborate documentation and how-to's on company and third-party applications.
- Mobile Device Management administration with Jamf and Apple Configurator.
- Maintain company website on Joomla and distribute email campaigns on Mailchimp.
- Deploy, maintain and configure network infrastructure including: Ubiquiti access points, routers and switches.
- Set-up, maintain, and configured osTicket Support Ticket System.
- Integrated a third-party digital clock in/out system that optimized and reduced payroll preparation time.
- Coordinated with third-party providers to move company applications to the cloud.
- Fulfilled contracts with different providers ranging from computer equipment to third-party applications.
- Integrated a third-party mobile warehouse system that improved load times and reduced shipment errors.
- Successfully implemented and migrated user data to G Suite.

Rasmussen College, Bloomington, Minnesota

Peer Tutor - Remote

September 2016 - November 2017

Conducted one-on-one tutoring sessions with students, facilitated the implementation of solutions to common software development issues by reviewing code and promoting problem-solving skills.

- Documented, and tracked student performance on Google Sheets, and Brainfuse.
- Followed up with students and communicated with fellow tutors via email, phone and instant messaging.
- Provided new hire training, training on learning services and participated in mock sessions with new tutors.
- Completed and held CRLA Level 1 Certified Tutor by accumulating over 100 hours of tutoring sessions.
- Maintained learning services resources with up to date information, and validating url's.
- Attended various webinars that promoted critical thinking, learning skills, and role modeling.
- Participated on monthly staff meetings, and promoted department goals.

Experience (cont.)

GTS International, Inc, Hidalgo, Texas

Operations Coordinator

November 2011 - August 2013

Coordinated shipments to and from Mexico, managed delivery timelines, resolved customers inquires, created shipment orders.

- Maintained warehouse inventory up to date.
- Provided new hire training both on Traffic and Warehouse Department.
- Elaborated Shipper's Export Declaration throughout the Automated Export System.

Warehouse Specialist

September 2010 - November 2011

Performed different warehouse tasks that included fulfillment of shipment orders, loading and unloading of trucks, and monitored inventory.

- Certified Forklift Operator.
- Mapped warehouse floor to optimize loading times.
- Followed OSHA safety guidelines and best practices.

Casa SolSil, Cuauhtemoc, Mexico City

Assistant Clerk - Part time

September 2009 - November 2010

Assisted therapist in scheduling appointments and elaborating health/beauty products.

- Confirmed appointments and greeted patients.
- Received payments and performed bank deposits.
- Run errands with different providers.

GTS International, Inc, Hidalgo, Texas

Warehouse Assistant - Summer job

June 2007 - September 2007

Assisted warehouse staff on different tasks around the warehouse floor.

- Data entry of products into inventory system.
- Unloading and loading of products.
- Labeled, processed and fulfilled shipment orders.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, GPA 3.16

August 2012 - November 2017

Rasmussen College, Bloomington, Minnesota

Studies focused on Full-Stack Web Development, Enterprise Architecture and iOS Development.

- Courses: Cloud Computing, Application Architecture, Business Intelligence, Database Management.
- Projects:
- WareInv. Web application written in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL that allows users to track warehouse inventory.
- *RasTech.* iOS application written in Swift that allows users to see the degrees and their courses thought at Rasmussen College.

Certifications

Architecting with Google Cloud Platform by Google Cloud.

January 2019

Responsive Web Design by freeCodeCamp.

October 2018

Google IT Support Professional by Google.

September 2018

G Suite Administrator by Google Cloud.

July 2018

Level 1 Certified Tutor by the College Reading & Learning Association.

April 2017

Projects

Current

- Regina Fernanda. Designer's website/portfolio written in HTML, CSS (+Bootstrap) and JavaScript (+jQuery).
- Aplantate. Wordpress Site, SEO, AWS LightSail.
- Ashtangamor. Business landing page written in HTML and CSS (+Bootstrap).

Past

• Regina Fernanda: Designer's Landing page written in HTML, and CSS (+Bootstrap).